<Publish>
  <!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
  <ModId Value="84638" />
  <!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
  <DisplayName Value="Recolor" />
  <!--Short description of the mod-->
  <ShortDescription Value="Gives player control over single instance colors and/or color variations of most buidings, props, vehicles, plants, and trees." />
  <!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
  <!--LongDescription Value="A mod for changing colors in Cities Skylines 2" /-->
  <LongDescription>Panel, Picker, Painter

Gives player control over single instance colors for most buildings, vehicles, props, and a few other assets. Gives player control over color variations for the meshes for trees, plants, most buildings, vehicles, props, and a few other assets.

CloverPie has produced a colorful video demonstration with a pre-release version of the mod. Please watch on YouTube.

## Dependencies
Unified Icon Library

## Donations
If you want to say thank you with a donation you can do so on Paypal.

## Translations
I am looking for volunteers to help translate the mod into the other languages. For those interested please find the project in the crowdin or discord link. CSL2:CODEMODS -&gt; mods-wip -&gt; Recolor. Also see Crowdin link.
The mod is fully or partially available in the following languages: French, Polish, Brazilian Portuguese, Russian, Spanish, German, Chinese Simplified, and European Portuguese.

## Supplemental Mods
European Portuguese Localization and I18N Everywhere (Only needed for European Portuguese Translations)
  
# Detailed Description
## Recolor Panel Section
Adds a Recolor section to the top left panel when selecting an asset instance if the main mesh of that asset supports custom colors. This panel section has 3 color fields with Hue, Saturation, and Brightness sliders that will change up to three colors of the asset. The asset must have been designed to utilize customizable colors, not all assets utilize all 3 colors, and the parts affected by each color in the color set are predefined and cannot be changed. An unsupported color channel are often by default just white. 

The Recolor panel can control the single instance colors or color variations of all assets that utilize the matching mesh and color variation. Single instance colors of plants and trees is not currently supported. Color changes are immediately applied and saved into this save game. With a button press you can save color variations to the ModsData folder so that color variation will be a default for all other saves. These xml files can also be shared out of game. 

The panel features copy, paste, reset, swap channel functions. Sets of colors and single color fields can be independently copied and pasted, and are separate. The panel can be minimized when not being used. The panel has a color picker tool as an alternative to copy/paste. 

All vehicles from a specific service building can have an assigned color set which will affect existing and newly spawned vehicles from that service building.

All vehicles along an assigned route can have an assigned color set which will affect existing and newly spawned vehicles from that route.

While changing Single Instance colors on a prefab with Multiple Meshes, you can limit color changes to individual submeshes, matching submeshes, or all submeshes.

While changing Matching Color Variations on a prefab with Multiple Meshes, you are limited to only matching submeshes and it will not change all submeshes. You can pick which type of submesh to change. 

Optional Hexidecimal input for colors.

You can select NetLane fences and hedges placed by EDT or inside buildings using a tool activated by keyboard shortcut (default Alt + F).

## Color Painter Tool
The recolor panel has a button to activate the color painter tool. You can also use a customizable keyboard shortcut (default Shift + P). By default when activating the color painter tool the color set of the selected asset is copied automatically. This can be changed in settings. 

The color painter tool has similar functionality to the recolor panel but with a different workflow. It is faster but changes to the colors are not applied immediately, you must select the asset to apply changes. Paint tool mode uses left mouse button to change colors, and right mouse button to do a quick reset. Reset tool mode will only highlight assets that can be reset and uses left mouse button to apply the reset. You can copy/paste colors between the color painter tool and the Recolor panel. The color painter has its own color picker tool mode as an alternative to copy/paste. For even faster application you can change instance colors of buildings, props, and vehicles over a radius. You must choose the filter that you want to use between those three. 

Channels can be toggle with the painter, but may require knowing what channel affect what on the subjects.

## Limitations
* Not all buildings or props support custom colors because their mesh was not designed to support this. For instance most unique buildings were intended to be unique.
* To select sub-objects other than service upgrades and utilize the Recolor panel, you must enable DevUI Tab Menu -&gt; Simulation tab -&gt; Debug Toggle. The color painter can target sub-objects without debug toggle.

## Other Color Variation Mods
Other existing mods such as Tree Controller and Vehicle Variation Packs by Konsi/Mimonsi contain curated sets of color variations. This mod is intended to be the user override for those mods. You can still use those other mods that affect color variation, but this mod should take precedence if you've assigned an overriding color variation.

## Support
I will respond on the code modding channels on **Cities: Skylines Modding Discord**

## Credits 
* yenyang - Mod Author
* CloverPie - Testing, Feedback, Promotional Material, Logo.
* Chameleon TBN - Testing, Feedback, Icons, Logo.
* Tigon Ologdring - Project discussions, Feedback, Icon.
* HarborMasterJay, Sully, Dome - Testing, Feedback
* Klyte45, Algernon, T.D.W., krzychu124, Trejek, Triton Supreme, Konsi, and Quboid - Help with UI, Cooperative Development and Code Sharing
* Translators: enGendo87(Spanish), karmel68(Polish), baka-gourd and RilkeXS (Chinese Simplified), MarKing(Brazilian Portuguese), hitzu and slobodskoy (Russian), Morgan Touverey and Edou24 (French), Hendrix and KaeseMitKuchen (German), Ti4goc and Obelix  (European Portuguese), Hinanchovo (Korean)
* Bruceyboy24804, spacechad - Project discussions.
* Vecteezy.com as an image source for parts of Logo design.</LongDescription>
  <!--Thumbnail-->
  <Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
  <!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/aRowHousesSmall.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/bPanelExplanationWithLogo.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/midRiseApartmentsSmall.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/painterTool.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/zCampgroundWithLogo.png" />
  <!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
  <Tag Value="Code Mod" />
  <!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
  <ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/recolor.1694303/" />
  <!--Version of the mod-->
  <ModVersion Value="1.1.1" />
  <!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
  <GameVersion Value="1.2.*" />
  <!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
  <Dependency Id="74417" DisplayName="Unified Icon Library" Version="1.0.12" />
  <!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
  <ChangeLog># Patch v1.1.1
* Fix stroke dash array UI warning logs from loading color painter svg image. Fixes lag spike from opening panel.
* Added hidden setting that minimizes panel on game load if it was minimized when game was previously closed.
* Added setting that always minimizes panel on game start.
* Updated Localization.</ChangeLog>
  <!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon, buymeacoffee, kofi, crowdin, gitlab-->
  <ExternalLink Type="youtube" Url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2FX0UDSThmQ" />
  <ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/HTav7ARPs2" />
  <ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/yenyang/Recolor" />
  <ExternalLink Type="paypal" Url="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/YenyangsMods" />
  <ExternalLink Type="crowdin" Url="https://crowdin.com/project/csl2-mod-recolor" />
</Publish>