<Publish>
  <!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
  <ModId Value="84638" />
  <!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
  <DisplayName Value="Recolor" />
  <!--Short description of the mod-->
  <ShortDescription Value="Gives player control over single instance colors and/or color variations of most buidings, props, vehicles, plants, and trees." />
  <!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
  <!--LongDescription Value="A mod for changing colors in Cities Skylines 2" /-->
  <LongDescription>Panel, Picker, Painter

Gives player control over single instance colors for most buildings, vehicles, props, and a few other assets. Gives player control over color variations for the meshes for trees, plants, most buildings, vehicles, props, and a few other assets.

CloverPie has produced a colorful video demonstration with a pre-release version of the mod. Please watch on YouTube.

## Dependencies
Unified Icon Library

I18n Everywhere (Soft dependency required for loading languages other than English.)

## Donations
If you want to say thank you with a donation you can do so on Paypal.

## Translations
I am looking for volunteers to help translate the mod into the other languages. For those interested please find the project in the crowdin or discord link. CSL2:CODEMODS -&gt; mods-wip -&gt; Recolor. Also see Crowdin link.
The mod is fully or partially available in the following languages: French, Polish, Brazilian Portuguese, Russian, Spanish, German, Chinese Simplified, and European Portuguese.

## Supplemental Mods
European Portuguese Localization (Only needed for European Portuguese Translations)
  
# Detailed Description
## Recolor Panel Section
Adds a Recolor section to the top left panel when selecting an asset instance if the main mesh of that asset supports custom colors. This panel section has 3 color fields with Hue, Saturation, and Brightness sliders that will change up to three colors of the asset. The asset must have been designed to utilize customizable colors, not all assets utilize all 3 colors, and the parts affected by each color in the color set are predefined and cannot be changed. An unsupported color channel are often by default just white. 

The Recolor panel can control the single instance colors or color variations of all assets that utilize the matching mesh and color variation. Single instance colors of plants and trees is not currently supported. Color changes are immediately applied and saved into this save game. With a button press you can save color variations to the ModsData folder so that color variation will be a default for all other saves. These xml files can also be shared out of game. 

The panel features copy, paste, and reset functions. Sets of colors and single color fields can be independently copied and pasted, and are separate. The panel can be minimized when not being used. The panel has a color picker tool as an alternative to copy/paste. 

## Color Painter Tool
The recolor panel has a button to activate the color painter tool. You can also use a customizable keyboard shortcut (default Shift + P). By default when activating the color painter tool the color set of the selected asset is copied automatically. This can be changed in settings. 

The color painter tool has similar functionality to the recolor panel but with a different workflow. It is faster but changes to the colors are not applied immediately, you must select the asset to apply changes. Paint tool mode uses left mouse button to change colors, and right mouse button to do a quick reset. Reset tool mode will only highlight assets that can be reset and uses left mouse button to apply the reset. You can copy/paste colors between the color painter tool and the Recolor panel. The color painter has its own color picker tool mode as an alternative to copy/paste. For even faster application you can change instance colors of buildings, props, and vehicles over a radius. You must choose the filter that you want to use between those three. 

## Limitations
* Not all buildings or props support custom colors because their mesh was not designed to support this. For instance most unique buildings were intended to be unique.
* NetLane Fencing from EDT is not supported, and this cannot change their colors. Fencing props with color variations can be changed.
* This mod has not yet been designed to handle experimental custom assets from unfinished editor featuring multiple meshes. Trying to use this mod on these types of assets may have varying and undesirable results.
* To select sub-objects other than service upgrades and utilize the Recolor panel, you must enable DevUI Tab Menu -&gt; Simulation tab -&gt; Debug Toggle. The color painter can target sub-objects without debug toggle.

## Other Color Variation Mods
Other existing mods such as Tree Controller and Vehicle Variation Packs by Konsi/Mimonsi contain curated sets of color variations. This mod is intended to be the user override for those mods. You can still use those other mods that affect color variation, but this mod should take precedence if you've assigned an overriding color variation.

## Support
I will respond on the code modding channels on **Cities: Skylines Modding Discord**

## Credits 
* yenyang - Mod Author
* CloverPie - Testing, Feedback, Promotional Material, Logo.
* Chameleon TBN - Testing, Feedback, Icons, Logo.
* HarborMasterJay, Sully, Dome - Testing, Feedback
* Klyte45, Algernon, T.D.W., krzychu124, Trejek, Triton Supreme, Konsi, and Quboid - Help with UI, Cooperative Development and Code Sharing
* Translators: enGendo87(Spanish), karmel68(Polish), baka-gourd and RilkeXS (Chinese Simplified), MarKing(Brazilian Portuguese), hitzu and slobodskoy (Russian), Morgan Touverey (French), Hendrix and KaeseMitKuchen (German), Ti4goc (European Portuguese)
* Bruceyboy24804, spacechad, Tigon Ologdring - Project discussions.
* Vecteezy.com as an image source for parts of Logo design.</LongDescription>
  <!--Thumbnail-->
  <Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
  <!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/aRowHousesSmall.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/bPanelExplanationWithLogo.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/midRiseApartmentsSmall.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/painterTool.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Previews/zCampgroundWithLogo.png" />
  <!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
  <Tag Value="Code Mod" />
  <!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
  <ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/recolor.1694303/" />
  <!--Version of the mod-->
  <ModVersion Value="1.0.100" />
  <!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
  <GameVersion Value="1.2.*" />
  <!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
  <Dependency Id="74417" DisplayName="Unified Icon Library" Version="1.0.9" />
  <Dependency Id="75426" DisplayName="I18n EveryWhere" Version="1.2.0" />
  <!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
  <ChangeLog># Patch V1.1.0
* You can select NetLane fences and hedges placed by EDT or inside buildings using a tool activated by keyboard shortcut.
* Color picker and painter can select Netlane fences and hedges.
* When changing colors, SubObject and SubLanes colors will update immediately.
* Color painter can toggle channels.
* Alpha transparancy sliders added.
* Optional Hexadecimal input fields.</ChangeLog>
  <!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon, buymeacoffee, kofi, crowdin, gitlab-->
  <ExternalLink Type="youtube" Url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2FX0UDSThmQ" />
  <ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/HTav7ARPs2" />
  <ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/yenyang/Recolor" />
  <ExternalLink Type="paypal" Url="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/YenyangsMods" />
  <ExternalLink Type="crowdin" Url="https://crowdin.com/project/csl2-mod-recolor" />
</Publish>